Guide to the Réunion Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Réunion collection
1969-1992
1972-1986
MS 1535
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.77
(4 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to political and social conditions in Réunion.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection (MS 605); Pamphlet Collection (MS 1351); African Postcard Collection (MS 1575). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to political and social conditions in Réunion.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Women -- Réunion; Réunion -- Description and travel; Réunion -- Politics and government
- Original Accession, 1973-1986
  - La Réunion: Les problèmes posés par l'Intégration, by Albert Ramassamy, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General information pamphlets; brochures, booklets, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Nou Rényoné Koméla: literary journal, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Héva: le témoignage des femmes: journal de l'Union des Femmes de la Réunion (UFR), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Règlement Intérieur, Conseil Régional, République Française, 1986 September 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Additional Material, 1987-1992; Accession 1998-M-029
  - Le Cirque de Mafate [Les Cahiers de Notre Histoire], 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Joseph Hubert Naturaliste [Les Cahiers de Notre Histoire], 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Région Réunion, [1987?] (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional Material, 1972-1991; Accession 2010-M-113
  - Heva: le témoignage des femmes, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jeunesse Marxiste, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Documentation Economique et Sociale de la Réunion, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Le conservatoire de l'espace littoral et des rivages lacustres a la Réunion (Conseil des Rivages Française de l'Ocean Indien), undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Saint-Pierre de 1970 à nos jours, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lêpâdâs ek Liberte (2 copies), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional material, 1969-1976; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1969-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)